<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baosen Zhang</title>
    <description>Baosen Zhang is an Associate Professor in the Electrical and Computer Engineering Department at the University of Washington.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 21:42:10 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 21:42:10 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three papers in PSCC</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have three papers that will appear at the PSCC Conferece:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jiang2024oscillationsaware&quot;&gt;Y. Jiang, H. Min, and B. Zhang, “Oscillations-Aware Frequency Security Assessment via Efficient Worst-Case Frequency Nadir Computation,” in &lt;i&gt;Power Systems Computation Conference (PSCC)&lt;/i&gt;, 2024. &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;jiang2024oscillationsaware-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;javascript:toggleDiv(&apos;jiang2024oscillationsaware-bibtex&apos;)&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;jiang2024oscillationsaware-bibtex&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{jiang2024oscillationsaware,
  title = {Oscillations-Aware Frequency Security Assessment via Efficient Worst-Case Frequency Nadir Computation},
  author = {Jiang, Yan and Min, Hancheng and Zhang, Baosen},
  year = {2024},
  booktitle = {Power Systems Computation Conference (PSCC)},
  link = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16765},
  blog = {2024-4-11-PSCC}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16765&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

  &lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;li2024socially&quot;&gt;J. Li, M. Motoki, and B. Zhang, “Socially Optimal Energy Usage via Adaptive Pricing,” in &lt;i&gt;Power Systems Computation Conference (PSCC)&lt;/i&gt;, 2024. &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;li2024socially-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;javascript:toggleDiv(&apos;li2024socially-bibtex&apos;)&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;li2024socially-bibtex&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{li2024socially,
  title = {Socially Optimal Energy Usage via Adaptive Pricing},
  author = {Li, Jiayi and Motoki, Matthew and Zhang, Baosen},
  year = {2024},
  booktitle = {Power Systems Computation Conference (PSCC)},
  link = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.13254},
  blog = {2024-4-11-PSCC}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.13254&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

  &lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;stiasny2023pinnsim&quot;&gt;J. Stiasny, B. Zhang, and S. Chatzivasileiadis, “PINNSim: A Simulator for Power System Dynamics based on Physics-Informed Neural Networks,” in &lt;i&gt;Power Systems Computation Conference (PSCC)&lt;/i&gt;, 2024. &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;stiasny2023pinnsim-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;javascript:toggleDiv(&apos;stiasny2023pinnsim-bibtex&apos;)&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;stiasny2023pinnsim-bibtex&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;@inproceedings{stiasny2023pinnsim,
  title = {PINNSim: A Simulator for Power System Dynamics based on Physics-Informed Neural Networks},
  author = {Stiasny, Jochen and Zhang, Baosen and Chatzivasileiadis, Spyros},
  year = {2024},
  booktitle = {Power Systems Computation Conference (PSCC)},
  link = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.10256},
  blog = {2024-4-11-PSCC}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.10256&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

  &lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/04/PSCC</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/04/PSCC</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CEI Distinguished Postdoctoral Fellowship at the University of Washington</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Clean Energy Institute at the University of Washington is now accepting applications for our CEI Distinguished Postdoctoral Fellowship. We invite innovative, exceptionally talented researchers who have recently received their Ph.D. degree (or foreign equivalent) to apply for full-time postdoctoral fellowship positions at the UW’s Seattle campus. The Fellowship is a full-time, 12-month position at the rank of Research Associate. The salary range is $75,000– $100,000 depending on the qualifications and scope of the research proposed by the applicant. Reappointment for an additional year is possible depending upon mutual agreement and funding availability. The Fellowship carries an annual discretionary research budget of $10,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cei.washington.edu/research/postdoctoral/distinguished-postdoctoral-fellowship/&quot;&gt;UW CEI website&lt;/a&gt; to learn more, or apply directly via &lt;a href=&quot;https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://apply.interfolio.com/143751__;!!K-Hz7m0Vt54!gnS48ygEN13HLIcKuz8-Gd4fmgbaoy_BWWndK2pf6DGYKBIjDKsRnFR9urDPegYEAG1-s0Akyr_tXFE$&quot;&gt;Interfolio&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/04/CEI</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/04/CEI</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SIGEnergy Rising Star Award</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m honored to receive the 2022 SIGEnergy Rising Star Award. For more information, please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://energy.acm.org/2023/01/31/sigenergy-rising-star-award-2022-winner/&quot;&gt;https://energy.acm.org/2023/01/31/sigenergy-rising-star-award-2022-winner/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/SigEnergy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/02/SigEnergy</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on Efficient Reinforcement Learning Through Trajectory Generation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A key barrier to using reinforcement learning (RL) in many real-world applications is the requirement of a large number of system interactions to learn a good control policy. Off-policy and Offline RL methods have been proposed to reduce the number of interactions with the physical environment by learning control policies from historical data. However, their performances suffer from the lack of exploration and the distributional shifts in trajectories once controllers are updated. Moreover, most RL methods require that all states are directly observed, which is difficult to be attained in many settings. To overcome these challenges, we propose a trajectory generation algorithm, which adaptively generates new trajectories as if the system is being operated and explored under the updated control policies. Motivated by the fundamental lemma for linear systems, assuming sufficient excitation, we generate trajectories from linear combinations of historical trajectories. For linear feedback control, we prove that the algorithm generates trajectories with the exact distribution as if they are sampled from the real system using the updated control policy. In particular, the algorithm extends to systems where the states are not directly observed. Experiments show that the proposed method significantly reduces the number of sampled data needed for RL algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/L4DC_trajectory</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/01/L4DC_trajectory</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
