<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baosen Zhang</title>
    <description>Baosen Zhang is an Associate Professor in the Electrical and Computer Engineering Department at the University of Washington.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:59:24 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:59:24 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Microsoft Research is looking for interns to work on AI and power.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Research (MSR) is seeking Research Interns to work at the intersection of artificial intelligence (AI) and electricity infrastructure planning. Research Interns will join ongoing research efforts that explore how AI—especially large language models (LLMs) and agentic AI systems—can support planning, permitting, siting, grid modeling, and decision-making in electricity systems. The team is fantastic and I will be involved as well. Application link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://apply.careers.microsoft.com/careers/job/1970393556734896&quot;&gt;https://apply.careers.microsoft.com/careers/job/1970393556734896&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2026/01/MSR_intern</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2026/01/MSR_intern</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Base Power Company is Looking for Interns</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two of my former students, Chase Dowling and Daniel Tabas, are looking for interns. Specifically, they are looking for people to design and implementation of sequential decision algorithms for trading energy and ancillary services in the Texas markets. They are great people and I’m sure the problem is interesting! For more information see this &lt;a href=&quot;https://job-boards.greenhouse.io/basepowercompany/jobs/4474393008&quot;&gt;job posting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/01/Basepower</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/01/Basepower</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We are accepting CEI Distinguished Postdoctoral Fellowship Again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Clean Energy Institute at the University of Washington is now accepting applications for our CEI Distinguished Postdoctoral Fellowship. We invite innovative, exceptionally talented researchers who have recently received their Ph.D. degree (or foreign equivalent) to apply for full-time postdoctoral fellowship positions at the UW’s Seattle campus. The Fellowship is a full-time, 12-month position at the rank of Research Associate. The salary range is $75,000– $100,000 depending on the qualifications and scope of the research proposed by the applicant. Reappointment for an additional year is possible depending upon mutual agreement and funding availability. The Fellowship carries an annual discretionary research budget of $10,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cei.washington.edu/research/postdoctoral/distinguished-postdoctoral-fellowship/&quot;&gt;UW CEI website&lt;/a&gt; to learn more, or apply directly via &lt;a href=&quot;https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://apply.interfolio.com/159460__;!!K-Hz7m0Vt54!gQeGYUx6MyLTC3t0cjNn3KUCzU2uUADWU_n1ee0xy2CurbveaY8fiPgB3C_PeoQXBhhjKU4kaE_quwxESnuEEnoFd03dwQ$&quot;&gt;Interfolio&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/12/CEI</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/12/CEI</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recent students and postocs starting their own labs: Wenqi Cui at NYU, Zixiao Ma at Binghamton and Yan Jiang at CUHK.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Three people from the group at starting their career as Assistant Professors: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wenqi-cui.github.io/&quot;&gt;Wenqi Cui (NYU)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://zixiaoma1991.github.io/&quot;&gt;Zixiao Ma (Binghamton)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sse.cuhk.edu.cn/en/teacher/1757&quot;&gt;Yan Jiang (CUHK)&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re a student thinking about where to go for graduate schools, please consider them!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/04/Students</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/04/Students</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
