<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baosen Zhang</title>
    <description>Baosen Zhang is an Associate Professor in the Electrical and Computer Engineering Department at the University of Washington.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 21:33:10 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 21:33:10 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Decentralized Safe Reinforcement Learning for Voltage Control</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As more inverter-connected renewable resources are integrated into the grid, frequency stability may degrade because of the reduction in mechanical inertia and damping. A common approach to mitigate this degradation in performance is to use the power electronic interfaces of the renewable resources for primary frequency control. Since inverter-connected resources can realize almost arbitrary responses to frequency changes, they are not limited to reproducing the linear droop behaviors. To fully leverage their capabilities, reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a popular method to design nonlinear controllers to optimize a host of objective functions.
Because both inverter-connected resources and synchronous generators would be a significant part of the grid in the near and intermediate future, the learned controller of the former should be stabilizing with respect to the nonlinear dynamics of the latter. To overcome this challenge, we explicitly engineer the structure of neural network-based controllers such that they guarantee system stability by construction, through the use of a Lyapunov function. A recurrent neural network architecture is used to efficiently train the controllers. The resulting controllers only use local information and outperform optimal linear droop as well as other state-of-the-art learning approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/02/Voltage</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/02/Voltage</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on Predicting Power System Dynamics and Transients using a Frequency Domain Approach</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The dynamics of power grids are governed by a large number of nonlinear ordinary differential equations (ODEs). To safely operate the system, operators need to check that the states described by this set of ODEs stay within prescribed limits after various faults. Limited by the size and stiffness of the ODEs, current numerical integration techniques are often too slow to be useful in real-time or large-scale resource allocation problems. In addition, detailed system parameters are often not exactly known. Machine learning approaches have been proposed to reduce the computational efforts, but existing methods generally suffer from overfitting and failures to predict unstable behaviors.
This paper proposes a novel framework for power system dynamic predictions by learning in the frequency domain. The intuition is that although the system behavior is complex in the time domain, there are relatively few dominate modes in the frequency domain. Therefore, we learn to predict by constructing neural networks with Fourier transform and filtering layers. System topology and fault information are encoded by taking a multi-dimensional Fourier transform, allowing us to leverage the fact that the trajectories are sparse both in time and spatial (across different buses) frequencies. We show that the proposed approach does not need detailed system parameters, speeds up prediction computations by orders of magnitude and is highly accurate for different fault types. Joint work with Microsoft Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/Nature_sub</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/Nature_sub</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on A Lyapunov Approach for Optimal Frequency Control using Reinforcement Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As more inverter-connected renewable resources are integrated into the grid, frequency stability may degrade because of the reduction in mechanical inertia and damping. A common approach to mitigate this degradation in performance is to use the power electronic interfaces of the renewable resources for primary frequency control. Since inverter-connected resources can realize almost arbitrary responses to frequency changes, they are not limited to reproducing the linear droop behaviors. To fully leverage their capabilities, reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a popular method to design nonlinear controllers to optimize a host of objective functions.
Because both inverter-connected resources and synchronous generators would be a significant part of the grid in the near and intermediate future, the learned controller of the former should be stabilizing with respect to the nonlinear dynamics of the latter. To overcome this challenge, we explicitly engineer the structure of neural network-based controllers such that they guarantee system stability by construction, through the use of a Lyapunov function. A recurrent neural network architecture is used to efficiently train the controllers. The resulting controllers only use local information and outperform optimal linear droop as well as other state-of-the-art learning approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/12/Lya-copy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/12/Lya-copy</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on Solving ACOPF Iteratively to get Global Optimal Solutions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The existence of multiple solutions to AC optimal power flow (ACOPF) problems has been noted for decades. Existing solvers are generally successful in finding local solutions, which are stationary points but may not be globally optimal. In this paper, we propose a simple iterative approach to find globally optimal solutions to ACOPF problems. First, we call an existing solver for the ACOPF problem. From the solution and the associated dual variables, we form a partial Lagrangian. Then we optimize this partial Lagrangian and use its solution as a warm start to call the solver again for the ACOPF problem. By repeating this process, we can iteratively improve the solution quality, moving from local solutions to global ones. We show the effectiveness our algorithm on standard IEEE networks. The simulation results show that our algorithm can escape from local solutions to achieve global optimums within a few iterations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/Iterative</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/Iterative</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
