<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baosen Zhang</title>
    <description>Baosen Zhang is an Assistant Professor in the Electrical and Computer Engineering Department at the University of Washington. 
</description>
    <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 06:23:18 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 06:23:18 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Postdoc Position in Machine Learning for Power Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Arizona State University and the University of Washington have a joint opening for a full-time postdoctoral scholar. The postdoc will work with Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;https://urldefense.com/v3/__http://www.public.asu.edu/*yweng2/__;fg!!IKRxdwAv5BmarQ!JNpl10chHomq64rgcMHoxkesSSHZuOmQczrrY39lbPj3as7rd0CmQXoucD3e15JesEZX_g$&quot;&gt;Yang Weng&lt;/a&gt; and Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;https://urldefense.com/v3/__http://zhangbaosen.github.io/__;!!IKRxdwAv5BmarQ!JNpl10chHomq64rgcMHoxkesSSHZuOmQczrrY39lbPj3as7rd0CmQXoucD3e15JJtIUHZQ$&quot;&gt;Baosen Zhang&lt;/a&gt; on the broad topic of machine learning for power systems operation. The anticipated start time is the spring or summer of 2021. If interested, please send your CV to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Yang.Weng@asu.edu&quot;&gt;yang.weng@asu.edu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:zhangbao@uw.edu&quot;&gt;zhangbao@uw.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/12/postdoc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/12/postdoc</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on A Lyapunov Approach for Optimal Frequency Control using Reinforcement Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The increase in penetration of inverter-based resources provide us with more flexibility in frequency regulation of power systems in addition to conventional linear droop controllers. Because of the fast power electronic interfaces, inverter-based resources can be used to realize complex control functions and potentially offer large gains in performance compared to linear controllers. Reinforcement learning has emerged as popular method to find these nonlinear controllers by parameterizing them as neural networks.
The key challenge with learning based approach is that stability constraints are difficult to enforce on the learned controllers. In addition, optimizing the controllers are nontrivial because of the time-coupled dynamics of power systems. In this paper, we propose to explicitly engineer the structure of neural network based controllers such that they guarantee system stability for all topologies and parameters. This is done by using a Lyapunov function to guide their structures. A recurrent neural network based reinforcement learning architecture is used to efficiently train the weights of controllers. The resulting controllers only use local information and outperform linear droop as well as strategies learned purely by using reinforcement learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cui2020reinforcement&quot;&gt;W. Cui and B. Zhang, “Reinforcement Learning for Optimal Frequency Control: A Lyapunov Approach,” &lt;i&gt;arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.05654&lt;/i&gt;. 2020. &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;cui2020reinforcement-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;javascript:toggleDiv('cui2020reinforcement-bibtex')&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;cui2020reinforcement-bibtex&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;@misc{cui2020reinforcement,
  title = {Reinforcement Learning for Optimal Frequency Control: A Lyapunov Approach},
  author = {Cui, Wenqi and Zhang, Baosen},
  year = {2020},
  journal = {arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.05654},
  link = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.05654},
  blog = {2020-09-22-2}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.05654&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

  &lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/09/Lya</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/09/Lya</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on Provable Guarantees using Machine Learning for DCOPF</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The DC optimal power flow (DCOPF) problem is a fundamental problem in power systems operations and planning. With high penetration of uncertain renewable resources in power systems, DCOPF needs to be solved repeatedly for a large amount of scenarios, which can be computationally challenging. As an alternative to iterative solvers, neural networks are often trained and used to solve DCOPF. These approaches can offer orders of magnitude reduction in computational time, but they cannot guarantee generalization, and small training error does not imply small testing errors. In this work, we propose a novel algorithm for solving DCOPF that guarantees the generalization performance. First, by utilizing the convexity of DCOPF problem, we train an input convex neural network. Second, we construct the training loss based on KKT optimality conditions. By combining these two techniques, the trained model has provable generalization properties, where small training error implies small testing errors. In experiments, our algorithm improves the optimality ratio of the solutions by a factor of five in comparison to end-to-end models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;zhang2020convex&quot;&gt;L. Zhang, Y. Chen, and B. Zhang, “A Convex Neural Network Solver for DCOPF with Generalization Guarantees,” &lt;i&gt;arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.09109&lt;/i&gt;, 2020. &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;zhang2020convex-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;javascript:toggleDiv('zhang2020convex-bibtex')&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;zhang2020convex-bibtex&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;@article{zhang2020convex,
  title = {A Convex Neural Network Solver for DCOPF with Generalization Guarantees},
  author = {Zhang, Ling and Chen, Yize and Zhang, Baosen},
  year = {2020},
  journal = {arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.09109},
  link = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.09109},
  blog = {2020-09-22-1}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.09109&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

  &lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/09/DCOPF</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/09/DCOPF</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on Load Forecasting During the COVID-19 Pandemic Using Mobility Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently posted a preprint &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.08826&quot;&gt;Using Mobility for Load Forecasting During the COVID-19 Pandemic&lt;/a&gt; on Arxiv. We proposed a novel load forecasting method to use the mobility data and transfer learning to help forecast the volatile load during the pandemic. Code and dataset are found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chennnnnyize/Load-Forecasting-During-COVID-19&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This result is also &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2020/06/18/ai-model-uses-smartphone-location-data-to-predict-power-grid-usage/&quot;&gt;featured in VentureBeat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/07/Nature_energy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/07/Nature_energy</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yuanyuan Shi to Join UCSD as an Assistant Professor </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats to &lt;a href=&quot;http://shiyuanyuan.site/&quot;&gt;Yuanyuan&lt;/a&gt; who will join ECE at University of California, San Diego as an Assistant Professor after a postdoc at Caltech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/07/Yuanyuan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/07/Yuanyuan</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paper on Learning to Solve Network Flow Problems via Neural Decoding</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Problems in power systems and operations research require repeatedly solving large-scale linear programming problems with a large number of different inputs. In energy systems with high levels of uncertain renewable resources, tens of thousands of scenarios may need to be solved every few minutes. Standard iterative algorithms for linear network flow problems, even though highly efficient, becomes a bottleneck in these applications. In this work, we propose a novel learning approach to accelerate the solving process. By leveraging the rich theory and economic interpretations of LP duality, we interpret the output of the neural network as a noisy codeword, where the codebook is given by the optimization problem’s KKT conditions. We propose a feedforward decoding strategy that finds the optimal set of active constraints. This design is error correcting and can offer orders of magnitude speedup compared to current state-of-the-art iterative solvers, while providing much better solutions in terms of feasibility and optimality compared to end-to-end learning approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;chen2020learning&quot;&gt;Y. Chen and B. Zhang, “Learning to Solve Network Flow Problems via Neural Decoding,” &lt;i&gt;arXiv preprint arXiv:2002.04091&lt;/i&gt;, 2020. &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;chen2020learning-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;javascript:toggleDiv('chen2020learning-bibtex')&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;chen2020learning-bibtex&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;@article{chen2020learning,
  title = {Learning to Solve Network Flow Problems via Neural Decoding},
  author = {Chen, Yize and Zhang, Baosen},
  journal = {arXiv preprint arXiv:2002.04091},
  year = {2020},
  link = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.04091},
  blog = {2020-02-20}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.04091&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

  &lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/02/ICML</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/02/ICML</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Input Convex Neural Networks for Optimal Voltage Regulation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The increasing penetration of renewables in distribution networks calls for faster and more advanced voltage regulation strategies. A promising approach is to formulate the problem as an optimization problem, where the optimal reactive power injection from inverters are calculated to maintain the voltages while satisfying power network constraints. However, existing optimization algorithms require the exact topology and line parameters of underlying distribution system, which are not known for most cases and are difficult to infer. In this paper, we propose to use specifically designed neural network to tackle the learning and optimization problem together. In the training stage, the proposed input convex neural network learns the mapping between the power injections and the voltages. In the voltage regulation stage, such trained network can find the optimal reactive power injections by design. We also provide a practical distributed algorithm by using the trained neural network. Theoretical bounds on the representation performance and learning efficiency of proposed model are also discussed. Numerical simulations on multiple test systems are conducted to illustrate the operation of the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;chen2020input&quot;&gt;Y. Chen, Y. Shi, and B. Zhang, “Input Convex Neural Networks for Optimal Voltage Regulation,” 2020. &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;chen2020input-materials&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;nav nav-pills&quot;&gt;
    

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a data-toggle=&quot;collapse&quot; href=&quot;javascript:toggleDiv('chen2020input-bibtex')&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;chen2020input-bibtex&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;pre class=&quot;collapse&quot;&gt;@article{chen2020input,
  title = {Input Convex Neural Networks for Optimal Voltage Regulation},
  author = {Chen, Yize and Shi, Yuanyuan and Zhang, Baosen},
  year = {2020},
  eprint = {2002.08684},
  link = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.08684},
  blog = {2020-02-19}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.08684&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    

  &lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/02/TCNS</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://faculty.washington.edu/zhangbao//blog/2020/02/TCNS</guid>
        
        
        <category>new</category>
        
        <category>papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
